A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Developing Countries Program, Budget Files FA521
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation records, Developing Countries Program, Budget Files
1966-1987
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation
FA521
8.33 Cubic Feet
Conditions Governing Access
Records more than 10 years old are open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Ford Foundation archive was deposited at RAC in 2011. Ford Foundation records, correspondence, reports, program files and officers papers were transferred to, and accessioned by, RAC beginning in 2011. Accessions continue as necessary.
Arrangement
Arranged in 2 series:
1. Budget Files.
2. Reports.
Scope and Contents
Contains Budget correspondence, reports, planning and review documentation.
- Budget Files, 1966-1987; I
  - OLAC Program Budget FY 1968 - Correspondence, 1966-1967 October (Box 1)
  - OLAC Program Budget FY 1968 - Correspondence, 1967 November-1968 (Box 1)
  - OLAC Program Budget FY 1969, 1967 November-1969 December (Box 1)
  - OLAC Program Budget FY 1970, 1968 October-1969 September (Box 1)
  - OLAC Field Office Budget Submissions FY 1970 (Box 2)
  - OLAC Program Budget FY 1971 - Correspondence, 1969 October-1971 (Box 2)
  - OLAC Mexico City Field Office Buget FY 1973 (Box 2)
  - Program Budget FY 1973 (Box 2)
  - International Division Budget Planning, 1973-1974 (Box 2)
  - OLAC Program Budget FY 1974 (Box 2)
  - Management Costs Budget FY 1974 (Box 3)
  - Program Management Budget File FY 1974 (Box 3)
  - Budget FY 1974 (Box 3)
  - W.D. Carmichael Budget Volume I, 1974 (Box 3)
  - W.D. Carmichael Budget Volume II, 1974 (Box 3)
  - W.D. Carmichael Budget Volume III, 1974 (Box 3)
  - OLAC Budget FY 1975 (Box 3)
  - Budget FY 1976 (Box 3)
  - OLAC Budget Planning FY 1976 (Box 3)
  - Budget Planning Exercise - Agriculture, 1976 (Box 4)
  - Budget Planning Exercise - Education, 1976 (Box 4)
  - Budget Planning Exercise - International Relations, 1976 (Box 4)
  - Budget Planning Exercise - Population, 1976 (Box 4)
  - Budget Planning Exercise - Social Sciences, 1976 (Box 4)
  - Budget Planning Exercise - General, 1977 (Box 4)
  - W.D. Carmichael Budget Volume IV, 1977 (Box 4)
  - Developing Countries Program Budget FY 1977 (Box 4)
  - Program Management Budget FY 1977 (Box 4)
  - OLAC Program Plans and Funding Request FY 1978-79 (Box 4)
  - Program Management Budget FY 1978 (Box 4)
  - Management Costs Budget FY 1978, 1977 September (Box 4)
  - OLAC Organization and Management, 1978-1982 (Box 4)
  - Proposed Program Budget FY 1980-81, 1979 June (Box 4)
  - Management Costs FY 1979 (Box 5)
  - OLAC Budget Documents FY 1979, 1979 October 1 (Box 5)
  - OLAC Program Review and Funding Request FY 1980-81, 1979 June (Box 5)
  - Management Costs Budget FY 1980, 1979 September (Box 5)
  - Management Costs Budget FY 1980, 1980 September 25-26 (Box 5)
  - OLAC Budget Documents and Briefing Materials, 1980 October (Box 5)
  - Proposed Program Budget FY 1982-83, 1981 June (Box 5)
  - Andes and Southern Cone Budget FY 1982-83, 1981 (Box 5)
  - Proposed Program Support Costs, Financial Management Costs, and General Management Costs FY 1982, 1981 September 23-25 (Box 5)
  - Proposed Spending Level, Budget and Program Plans FY 1984-85, 1983 March (Box 5)
  - Proposed Budget FY 1984-85, 1983 June (Box 5)
  - Proposed Modifications to FY 1984-85 Budget, 1983 September 28-29 (Box 5)
  - Proposed Spending Level FY 1986-87, 1985 September (Box 5)
  - Proposed Spending Level FY 1988-89, 1987 (Box 5)
  - Program Management Costs FY 1973 (Box 7)
  - Program Management Budget FY 1975 (Box 7)
  - Program Management Budget FY 1981 (Box 7)
- Reports, 1970-1981; II
  - Latin America - Towers, Perrin, Forster and Crosby Recommendations Report (Box 5)
  - Argentina Briefing Material - Visit of McGeorge Bundy, 1970 October 7-11 (Box 5)
  - Briefing Information for Argentina, 1970 (Box 5)
  - Brazil Program Principal Activities FY 1971 (Box 5)
  - Ford Foundation Colombia and Venezuela Annual Report Fy 1971 (Box 5)
  - Ford Foundation Peru Field Office Report FY 1971 (Box 5)
  - Ford Foundation Colombia and Venezuela Annual Report FY 1972 (Box 5)
  - Ford Foundation Lima Annual Report FY 1972, 1972 November (Box 5)
  - Ford Foundation Mexico City Field Office Annual Report FY 1972, 1973 January (Box 5)
  - International Urbanization Survey Findings and Recommendations, 1972 (Box 5)
  - Educational Television - A Policy Critique and Guide for Developing Countries, 1973 May (Box 5)
  - Ford Foundation Colombia and Venezuela Annual Report FY 1973, 1973 December (Box 5)
  - Ford Foundation Lima Field Office Annual Report FY 1973 (Box 5)
  - Ford Foundation Mexico City Field Office Annual Report FY 1973, 1973 December (Box 5)
  - Ford Foundation Colombia and Venezuela Annual Report FY 1975 (Box 6)
  - Ford Foundation Board of Trustees Future Program Planning Project, 1976 (Box 6)
  - Budgets, Assets and Expectations, 1976 December (Box 6)
  - Investment Policies, Spending Policies and Uncertainty, 1977 June (Box 6)
  - Future Investment and Spending Policies, 1978 March (Box 6)
  - The Ford Foundation's Future Financial Condition -- Some numerical projections, 1978 June (Box 6)
  - Brazil Program Discussions, 1980 October 20 (Box 6)
  - Mexico and Central America Briefing Materials, 1980 October 22 (Box 6)
  - Andes and the Southern Cone Review, 1980 October 23 (Box 6)
  - Program Review - Brazil, 1981 November (Box 6)